翻译            H小欠    小酸奶
翻译           HuskyDawg
翻译          喵星人卧底   阿斗
精校          米小勒
时间轴         想念Gallifrey的wholock     小黑
后期            咖啡·Lee
总监         米小勒
维 京     传 奇
第六季  第十九集
跟着我
Stay with me.
不要分散
Keep together.
放下武器
Put down your weapons.
他们不会攻击我们
They're not going to attack us.
佩米纽
Peminuit.
托尔薇
Torvi.
拉格纳
Ragnar.
我们不想和你们打架
我们宁愿讲和
来吧
来见见我们的酋长
佩克陶勒
我觉得他是想让我们和他一起去
I think he wants us to go with him.
-你确定吗  -确定
- Are you sure? - Yes.
那么我们走吧
Then let's go.
佩克陶勒
Pekitaulet.
这些是我的家人
我的长子  佩米纽
他的弟弟  韦基图
还有他的妻子  妮卡尼
你们是陌生人
我们会帮助你们
我们会确保你们不挨饿
我们会和你们做朋友  尊重你们
拉格纳
Ragnar.
开心
我们以为是海藻
侦察兵  到那边山坡上去
Scouts, ride up among those hills.
去看看有没有
See if there is any sightings
维京军队的踪影或迹象
or evidence of the Viking army.
是  阿尔弗雷德陛下
Yes, my Lord Alfred.
这边  这边
Here! Here!
你们几个  马上到山脊上去
You men! I want you on the ridge now!
防范一下
It's a precaution.
我怀疑  即使到现在
Even now, I suspect,
伊瓦尔的军队还是会去皇庭
Ivar's army will have reached the Royal Villa.
发现它被遗弃了
To find it deserted.
被抛弃了  而国王逃走了
Abandoned. The King fled.
他会尽情享受在那里放火的感觉
How greatly he will enjoy setting it afire.
亲爱的艾尔维斯
My sweet Elsewith,
你不可能比我自己更责怪我
you cannot fault me more than I fault myself.
留在皇庭的确是更勇敢的做法
It would have been a braver thing to remain at the villa.
我可以选择以身殉国
I could have chosen martyrdom.
我们都可以不昧着良心死掉
We could all have died with easy consciences.
请原谅我  我选择了更艰难的道路
Forgive me, I have chosen a harder path.
我选择挣扎求生
I have chosen to try and survive,
我认为上帝不会怪我
and I cannot think that God will blame me.
无论他责怪与否  我都打定主意了
And whether He blames me or not, my mind is set.
我们会与伊瓦尔
We will meet Ivar's army at a time
在我们选定的时间地点相遇
and place of our choosing.
虽然我对这场决战心存畏惧
In this final battle, which God knows I dread,
我坚信我们会赢
I believe we shall be victorious.
如果我不是全心忠于这个信念
If I did not believe it with all my heart,
我们不可能还走到这一步
then we would not be here.
阿门
Amen.
千万保佑
A thousand times, Amen.
来
Here.
你为什么不和我说话了
Why don't you talk anymore?
有什么好说的
What is there to talk about?
我瞎了  看不到
I am blind. I cannot see.
我看不到周围的事
I do not know what is happening around me.
你也从来不告诉我
And you never share.
好吧
Very well.
如果能让你开心点
If it means anything to you,
这只是其中之一
amongst other things,
我已经派了信任的人
I have dispatched a trusted fellow
去了丹麦
to go to that place in Denmark
那的国王已经皈依了基督教
where the King has been converted to Christianity.
我只能做到这步了
I thought it was the least I could do.
那这个"信任的人"
And what is this "Trusted fellow"
要去干什么
supposed to do?
当然是去刺杀国王
Assassinate the King, of course.
保护传统我们人人有责
We all have a duty to preserve the old ways.
你把所有的事都定了
You take all the decisions.
那让你来你会反对吗
Would you have objected to that?
就算我反对
If I had objected,
能有什么不同吗
would it have made any difference?
放这来  盖上它
Place it down here and cover it up.
奥莱格
Orlyg.
上一边去
Go away.
你为什么要哭
Why are you crying?
事情还能更糟吗
How can things be worse than this?
我们在这如同空气
We don't exist here.
我们什么都没了
We have lost everything.
我有获得自由的机会
I can be free.
真的吗  那要怎么做
Really? How?
他们给了你翅膀吗
Do they give you wings?
你能飞走
Can you fly away?
不
No
只要我为埃里克大人办一件事
I can be free if I do something for Lord Erik.
那你要做什么事
What do you have to do?
我不能说
I can't say.
你告诉我吧
You better say it,
我也想获得自由
because I want to be free, too.
人不自由还有什么意义
It's the only thing that matters!
我必须杀掉英格丽皇后
I have to kill Queen Ingrid.
好
Very well.
那我们一起来办
Then we'll do it together.
森林怎么了
What is it about the forests?
有人去森林里采蘑菇
People go into the forest to collect mushrooms
顺便去打点猎  然后再也没回来
or capture a stray animal, and they never return.
森林里有一些生物
There are creatures in the forest.
只要听到你们的脚步声
Strange creatures who spring up out of the ground
奇怪的生物就会从地里冒出来
if they hear your footsteps.
恶魔就住在森林里
The Devil himself lives in the forest...
他在里面徘徊
and he walks up and down in it.
陛下
My Lord.
请坐
Please, sit.
你现在省点力气比较好
You'll need your strength.
高兴点  你们这些人
Be of good cheer. All of you.
要相信上帝  不要害怕
Put your faith in God, and be not afraid.
我喜欢这些人
I like these people.
我不觉得他们会伤害我们
I don't believe they mean us any harm.
我同意
I agree.
我也觉得我们会需要他们的帮助
I also think we will need their help
在这里生存下去
if we are to survive here.
那就以友善回报他们
Then let's return their hospitality
邀请他们来访
and invite them to visit us.
没错  我们应该这样做
Yes, we should do that.
那个酋长会讲我们的语言
The sagamaw spoke words in our language.
怎么可能
How is that possible?
你好
Hello.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
这是铁做的  铁
It is made of iron. Iron.
铁
Iron
都在这里了
Everything is here.
我的故事
The story of myself.
我们一族的故事
The story of my race.
这是我被烧伤的地方
Here is where I was burned.
火焰灼烧了我
The flames consumed me.
烧毁了我的皮肤  将我重塑
Took away my skin, then re-made me.
画出了这些图案
In this image.
以这种方式
In this form.
但我的心就和你们的一样
But my heart is as old
古老坚强  朋友们
as your hearts, my friends.
好像木头一般
My heart is as old as wood.
就如同
As old...
森林中的
as a tall tree...
高大的树木一般
in the forest.
你会说我们的语言
我们听到了
能听懂吗
高兴
是谁和你说的
什么人还是神灵
谁很高兴
疯的
疯子
疯子在哪里
他在哪
金子  知道吗  金子
Gold. Yes? Gold.
金子
Gold.
在哪
Where?
金子在哪里
Where is the gold?
在哪
Where?
还是热的
Still warm.
带走
Take it.
保持队形
Hold the line!
保持住
Stay!
保持阵型
Keep formation!
稳住
Steady, I say!
听我号令
On me, men!
前进  保持队形
Go on, and hold the line!
听我号令
On me, men!
居然让它倒了
You let it fall!
把住  把住
Hold it! Hold it!
停
Halt!
立定
Stand...
不动
fast!
-拔剑  -亮出武器
- Swords! - Weapons!
-保护王后  -是  大人
- Guard the Queen. - Yes, my Lord.
-保护女王  -是  大人
- Protect the Queen. - Yes, my Lord.
一排  前进
Line one, advance!
我不明白  你说你想
I don't understand. What do you mean
"弄残"他们是什么意思
you want to "cripple" them?
如果我们杀掉这五百名撒克逊人
If we kill 500 Saxons,
那我们杀的也不过就五百人罢了
then we just kill 500 Saxons.
如果我们弄残这五百名撒克逊人
If we manage to cripple and injure 500 Saxons,
而不要伤了他们的性命
but not to kill them,
那就还需要一千名撒克逊人
then it will take 1,000 more Saxons
来救他们
to come and rescue them.
那么就有三倍于此的士兵的性命
That is three times the amount of warriors,
掌握在我们手里
and all at our mercy.
二排  前进
Line Two! Advance!
第三排  前进
Third Line! Advance!
三排  前进
Line Three! Advance!
但你怎么能确定阿尔弗雷德国王
But how can you be sure that King Alfred
会去救他们呢
will try to rescue them?
因为他是基督徒
Because he's a Christian.
他在意他们
He cares about them.
去救他们  去救他们
Help them! Help them!
把他们弄出来  去救他们
Get them out! Help them!
我们该怎么办  阿尔弗雷德陛下
What shall we do, my Lord Alfred?
陛下  我们是撤退还是前进
My Lord, do we go back or forward?
士兵们  与我一起
Soldiers! With me!
前进
Advance!
拼了
To battle!
出来战斗  你这个懦夫
Come out and fight, you coward!
伊瓦尔
Ivar!
然后
And then,
当阿尔弗雷德认为情况不会变得更糟时
when Alfred believes that it cannot get any worse...
我给他来个"雪上加霜"
I shall make it worse.
我要夺走他的王后
I shall take his Queen.
不可能的
Impossible.
她会受到严密的保护
She will be heavily protected.
我们怎么绕过女王的守卫
How do we get past the Queen's guard?
我是说
I mean, it's--
这很简单
That's simple.
我们直接走到他们面前  把她带走
We just walk right up to them and take her.
救救我们  上帝保佑
Help us! God help us!
上帝与我们同在  夫人
The Lord is with us, my Lady.
不
No!
按住她  让她别动
Hold her! Keep her still!
你疯了
You are crazy.
你真的很疯狂
You truly are crazy.
艾尔维斯
Elsewith!
等等
Here! Wait!
我看不到
I can't see.
我什么都看不到
I can't see anything.
就现在
Now!
后撤
Fall back!
快点
Come on!
赶紧离开这里
Let's get out of here!
哪边
Which way?
阿尔弗雷德陛下  我斗胆建议
My Lord Alfred, if I may advise you,
现在是撤退的好时机
now is the time to retreat.
我们已经找到了熟悉这片地方的人
We have found men who know this place
他可以带我们安全离开这个地方
and can guide us safely out of the plain.
我们不会撤退
We will not retreat.
陛下  如果我们继续留在这里  我担心会出事
My Lord, if we stay here, I fear things may end badly.
陛下  求您了
Lord, I beg you!
你听到我的命令了  我们不能撤退
You heard my command! We shall not retreat.
为什么
Why?
因为耶稣基督与我们同在
Because Jesus Christ is with us.
我看到他了
I saw him.
他就在战场上
He is on the battlefield,
我们不会离开他的身边
and we will not leave his side.
后撤
Fall back!
你要死了
You are dying.
瓦尔哈拉
Valhalla.
Valhalla?
那地方根本不存在
There is no such place.
你将会独自在这里死去
You will die here alone...
无人会记得你
and forgotten.
你好  兄弟
我来带你去瓦尔哈拉
众神之父在等你
兄弟
Brother.
瓦尔哈拉
Valhalla.
我们该怎样杀她
How do we kill her?
你想怎么杀她
How do you want to kill her?
我问你呢
I'm asking you.
我们毒死她
We can poison her.
你懂什么毒药
What poisons do you know?
我不认识毒药
I don't know any poisons.
我们可以捅死她
We can stab her.
你觉得能行吗
Do you think?
我觉得那是最好的办法
I think that is the best way.
但是埃里克必须远远离开
But Erik must be far away,
不能参与进来
and not involved.
我会让他和我睡觉
I'll get him to sleep with me.
他经常这样干
He does it all the time.
这样就不会在场了
He won't be there.
到时候就只有你和她了
Then it's just you and her.
我们要去哪里？
-Where are we goingto do it, huh?
有个地方
-Somewhere.
啊？
Huh?
我想现在就在这里做
l want to do it right here,right now.
附近有个地方
There's a place nearby.
很近地
It's close.
过来
come here
啊
Ah!
噢！回来
Oh! Come back.
到你的国王这来
Come back to your King!
你为什么想要杀了我  奥莱格
Why do you want to kill me, Orlyg?
谁让你杀了我
Who told you to kill me?
我知道你还在
I know you're still there.
我不会伤害你  我不会杀了你
I won't hurt you. I won't kill you.
我只希望你告诉我  谁让你杀了我
I just want you to tell me who asked you to kill me.
是埃里克吗
Was it Erik?
这就对了
There.
也不难猜嘛  对吗
That wasn't so hard, was it?
我知道你还在
I know you're here.
我能闻到你的味道
I can smell you.
我在这里
I'm here.
我本人就在这里
I myself am here.
叛徒
Traitor!
杀死他
Kill him.
叛徒
Traitor.
他罪有应得
He had it coming.
拉格纳
Ragnar.
这是我们的故事
This is our story.
疯子
Crazy man!
你好  弗洛基
Hello, Floki.
字幕调校 Yiliang